Inventory of the Sergio Fernández papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Sergio Fernández papers
1978-1992
93063
Fernández, Sergio (Fernández Fernández)
2 manuscript boxes (0.8 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Memoirs, speeches, decrees, proclamations, reports, and studies, relating to political conditions in Chile, administration of the Chilean government, and the transition from military to civilian rule in Chile, particularly during Fernández's service as minister of the interior.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1993.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
1939 January 28 Born, Punta Arenas, Chile
1959 Studied, Colegio Hispano Americano in Santiago
1963 Law degree, University of Chile
1976-1982 Minister of labor and social security
1978-1982 Minister of the interior
1987-1988 Minister of the interior
1990-2006 Senator
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection mainly relates to Sergio Fernández's role as the minister of the interior in Santiago, Chile from 1978 to 1982. It consists of interviews, speeches, notes, excerpts from books, and reports relating to political conditions in Chile, administration of the Chilean government, and the transition from military to civilian rule in Chile.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Chile--Politics and government--1973-1988.; Statesmen--Chile.
Collection Contents
- Reports, 1977-1992 (Box 1)
  - "Transicion a la democracia." Related to the transition to democracy during the Pinochet era. Includes interviews, personal accounts, speeches, and analyses of the political status and shifting ideology in Chile at the time. (Box 1)
    - Part I, 1977-1987 (Folder 1: 1)
    - Part II, 1977-1987 (Folder 1: 2)
    - Notes and appendices, 1974-1986 (Folder 1: 3)
  - Chapter from Los Hombres de la Transicion by Andres Bello, 1992 (Folder 1: 4)
  - Constitutional article outlines, 1983-1985 (Box 2)
    - "Estados de excepcion,", 1985 (Folder 2: 1)
    - "Educacion,", 1985 (Folder 2: 2)
    - "Sistema electoral,", 1985 (Folder 2: 3)
    - "Partidos politicos", 1983 (Folder 2: 4)
- Speeches, 1978-1981. (Box 3)
  Fernández's diaries containing his speeches during his time as minister of the interior.
  - 1978-1979 (Folder 3: 1)
  - 1979-1981 (2 copies) (Folder 3: 2-3)
  - 1980 (Folder 3: 4)
  - 1981 (Folder 3: 5)